{
  "reference_number": "5250",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We should not set any emissions target. This whole exercise is a pointless economy-killing virtue-signalling nonsense."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We should not set any emissions target."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We should not set any emissions target. This whole survey is biased in favour of the Green Party's position. What happened to our\n democracy? These people got less than 11% of the vote."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "When the solar minimums demonstrate that climate change is mainly driven by the Sun, then perhaps you'll realise that the science\n\n was flawed. As a doctor and a scientist I know that we are often wrong, and the climate research has been driven by political interests\n and ideologies for some years now. It is not based on rigorous science. I'm not saying climate change doesn't exist. It does. But the\n\n human impact is likely far smaller than the current flawed research suggests."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "This just gives the Labour Greens alliance the power to override the will of the people and exert their ideologically driven nonsense\n on the rest of us working New Zealanders."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "You are wrong and history will show that you attempted to kill New Zealand's economy to satisfy some.virtue signalling\nenvironmentalists."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Jobs for workers. If you people actually want to solve child poverty instead of talking about it, you need to grow the economy. Not stifle\n\nit with economic sabotage."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Yet another Commission wasting taxpayers hard earned dollars."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "More big salaries for friends of the Labour Party."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "This is ridiculous. Scientists are forecasting a solar minimum in the 2030s which will lead to global cooling on a massive scale."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "As I said before the science is not settled. For years now the climate change movement has silenced any scientists who try to speak\n\nout against this ideologically driven crusade. The whole premise is flawed. You people have no concept of basic science. The sun\nprovides 99.99% of the planet's energy. As much as humans can influence the planet, our major impact is on species and land use.\n\nSo you should be much more worried about mass extinctions and deforestation if you really care about the environment. Stopping a\nsmall country of 4.5 million people from functioning is going to do nothing when nations like the USA and China and India produce\n\nthousands of times more pollution. Once again this whole exercise is to make the Green Party happy and to give Jacinda an anointed\npath into a lifetime job at the United Nations. What a joke. History will judge you harshly for this.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
